[Respect Copyright, Everyone's Responsibility]
[저작권 보호는 모두의 책임입니다]
[The Eternal Fragrance]
[천향] [십사랑 소설  각색 작품]
[Episode 26]
[제26화]
On this mission, we must seize the Divine Tree's power
이번에는 반드시 건목의 힘을 빼앗아
and restore Dizang Sect's glory!
우리 지장문의 위세를 천하에 떨쳐야 한다
[The Divine Tree emerges]
[건목 현세]
Why does the Wuyue Court mobilize all forces
무월정이 이렇게 큰 소란을 피우고
to put Lifei on public trial
산해 양파를 불러 려비를 심판하려 하는데
before the Mountain and Sea Sects?
무슨 속셈입니까?
Master,
사부님
could they kill Lifei to grab
그 사람들 건목의 힘을 차지하려고
the Divine Tree's power?
려비를 죽이려는 겁니까?
From despair comes rebirth.
사지에 두고 살길을 찾게 하는 거다
There is surely sound sense
좌구 선생께서 이렇게 하시는 것도
in Mr. Zuo Qiu's arrangements.
분명 깊은 연유가 있을 것이다
Let us wait and watch.
우리는 두고 보도록 하자
Your Highness, what should we do now?
왕야, 이젠 어떡해야 합니까?
[The Divine Tree emerges]
[건목 현세]
Shall we gather men to rescue Lifei now?
인원을 모집해 려비를 구하러 갈까요?
Did the Chufeng Academy
이 소식은
leak this news?
추봉서원에서 내온 것이냐?
Yes.
예
Heaven watches over us and protects our clan.
하늘이시어, 우리 일족을 구원해 주셨네요
I firmly believe Your Lordship will gain a new life.
저는 존상님께서 다시 태어나실 거라 굳게 믿고 있었습니다
For five centuries,
오백 년 동안
I snuck into the Wuyue Court countless times,
수차례 무월정에 잠입해
only to search for Qingcheng and Your Lordship.
청성과 존상님의 행방만 찾아다녔습니다
Guangwei wounded me
마지막으로 잠입했을 때
on my last try.
광미 그 늙은 놈에게 상처도 입었습니다
Luckily, when his beloved disciple
다행히 그의 제자인
Yue Cailing chased me,
악채령이 저를 추격할 때
I seized her mortal vessel.
그녀의 몸을 빼앗았습니다
While recovering in Lugong Town,
육공진에서 상처를 치료하는 동안
I finally awaited your return.
드디어 존상님을 다시 만났습니다
This is great, my Lord.
정말 다행입니다, 존상님
So,
그래서
in the cave outside Lugong Town back then,
육공진 밖의 석굴에서
you already knew who I was.
이미 나를 알아봤단 말이냐?
You summoned the bone-devouring butterfly
서골접은 너였고
and made Songfeng fall into darkness, too.
송풍이 마도에 빠진 것도 네가 한 짓이었느냐?
Lei Xiuyuan,
뇌수원
how come you're conscious?
깨어있었다니
You were poisoned by Soul-Bewitching Vines.
분명 미혼만에 걸려있었는데
Mere Soul-Bewitching Vines
고작 미혼만 쯤으로
can never control me.
나를 통제하려고?
I never intended to control you.
저는 존상님을 통제하려는 게 아니라
I only hoped you'd remember you're Yecha.
존상님께서 본인이 야차인 걸 떠오르게 하려고 했습니다
All I've ever been
이번 생에
is Lei Xiuyuan.
난 뇌수원일 뿐이다
I don't understand.
사람이 되는 게
What joy is there in living as a human?
뭐가 좋습니까?
Do you still dream of staying forever with the Divine Tree?
존상님께서는 아직도 건목과 영원히 함께하시려는 겁니까?
I'm nothing like you.
나는 너랑 다르다
All I want is to live as a human,
나는 이 세상에서
an ordinary man in this world.
가장 평범한 사람이 되고 싶을 뿐이다
I made a promise to Lu,
나는 형님과의 약속을
yet I broke it.
어겼었다
This time,
이번엔
I'll not go back on my word.
절대 어기지 않을 것이다
You!
아니...
Rakshasa,
나찰
you've caused trouble time and again.
너는 여러 번 소란을 일으켰으니
I cannot spare you any longer.
이번만큼은 너를 살려둘 수 없다
Spare me, My Lord!
살려주십시오, 존상님
Show mercy!
살려주십시오
Cuixuan
강려비는
has captured Jiang Lifei.
취현한테 잡혔습니다
They will destroy the Divine Tree.
그들은 천 년 전처럼
Just like a thousand years ago,
건목을 죽일 겁니다
they will tear her apart and feed on her power
그녀의 혼백이 흩어질 때까지 토막 내고
until her soul vanishes completely.
나눠서 먹을 겁니다
My Lord!
존상님
You claim to be the top cultivator of the immortal sects.
선문 제일이라 자부하시면서
Why do you need my master's Senluo Grand Art?
왜 내 사부님의 삼라대법을 원하는 것이냐?
I see.
알겠다
Without the miniature realm
소천세계가 없어지고
and the wronged demon spirit,
원한에 잠긴 마령들이 사라졌으니
you can never cultivate and ascend.
선이 되어 비승할 수 없게 되었군
Stop daydreaming.
헛된 꿈 꾸지 말지
I'd rather die than give it to you.
난 죽어도 네게 주지 않을 거니까
We'll see
그럼
how tough you are.
네가 언제까지 버틸지 보자고
You imprisoned my master
내 사부님을 가둔 게
all for your greedy ambition.
그저 네 야심과 사욕 때문이잖아
Silence!
닥치거라
Everything I've done
본좌가 한 모든 일은
is for the immortal sects' grand cause.
선문 대업을 위해서다
Absorbing demon spirits
마령을 흡수하고
and slaying fellow cultivators
동문을 해치는 것도
are what you call the grand cause?
선문 대업이냐?
If they saw you kill my master
그들이 네가 내 사부님을 죽이고
and piles of bones in the miniature realm,
소천세계에 쌓여진 백골들을 보게 된다면
would they still buy your lies?
네 말을 계속 믿을 것 같으냐?
The miniature realm has been destroyed.
소천세계는 이미 파괴되었다
No one will believe a word
네가 하는 말들은
of what you say.
아무도 믿지 않을 것이다
True,
그래
I have no proof.
나한테 증거는 없다
But my master once said
하지만 사부님께서는
justice prevails in this world.
이 세상은 언제나 공평하다고 하셨다
What justice?
뭐가 공평한 거냐?
What even is justice?
공평이 무엇이란 말이냐
With the Fruit of the Divine Tree,
건목의 실만 있으면
I'll have endless spirit energy.
무궁무진한 영기를 얻게 된다
Once my cultivation reaches perfection
본좌의 공법이 완성되고
and I become an immortal,
선신을 이루게 된다면
every word and deed of mine shall be the rules
본좌의 말이 곧 규칙이 될 것이고
and the heavenly law itself.
천도가 될 것이다
Your master is far too naive
네 사부님은 너무 단순했지
to still believe in karmic retribution.
천하에 업보 따위가 있다고 믿었으니
You have no right to mention him!
무슨 자격으로 내 사부님을 입에 담느냐?
Stop struggling.
그만 저항하라
Even your master could not break these spirit-sealing chains,
이 쇄령사슬은 네 사부님조차도 풀지 못했는데
let alone you.
네가 어찌 풀 수 있겠느냐?
Master.
사부님
Don't move!
움직이지 마라
You tricked my master back by using your bond
넌 우리 사부님께서 품은 동문의 정을 이용해
as fellow disciples,
그를 속이고
locked him in the miniature realm, and tortured him.
소천세계에 가둬 갖은 고문을 했다
He was your senior brother.
네 사형이었단 말이다
Do you have any conscience left?
그한테 미안하지도 않으냐?
He wronged me first.
그가 먼저 나를 저버렸다
Years ago, Yecha left me gravely wounded.
그해 내가 야차에게 중상을 입었을 때
As my fellow disciple,
동문인 그가
he refused to heal me with the Divine Tree and demon spirits,
건목과 마령으로 나를 치료해 주지 않고
was obsessed with building the Outcast Tomb,
이민묘를 짓는 일에만 매달렸고
and sealed all demon spirits away.
마령을 봉인해 버렸다
Where
동문인 그는
was our bond back then?
우리 동문의 정을 생각한 적이 있었느냐?
He was stopping you from falling into darkness.
그건 네가 사로에 빠지는 걸 원치 않아서였다
He fell into darkness!
사로에 빠진 건 그다
His heart belonged to foreign lands,
그는 해외를 편들며
and he betrayed our sect,
사문을 배신해
leaving us his junior disciples to fend for ourselves.
우리 사제들을 알아서 죽게 내버려뒀다
I trusted him with all my heart once,
나는 그를 그토록 믿었었는데
yet
그는
look what he did.
무슨 짓을 했느냐?
He betrayed the sect.
사문을 배신했단 말이다
I hate how he cannot tell right from wrong.
나는 옳고 그름을 판단하지 못하는 그가 미웠다
He never repented even till his last breath.
그는 죽는 그날까지 잘못을 깨닫지 못했다
Narrow-minded wretches
속이 좁은 놈은
will never understand embracing all beings,
영원히 마음이 넓지 못하고
nor compassion for every living soul.
창생을 불쌍히 여기지 못한다
All you see
네 눈에는
is the fake miniature realm.
허황된 소천세계밖에 보이지 않고
You are filled with hatred,
속엔 원한으로 가득한 채
dwelling in suspicion and wariness all the time,
날마다 의심하고 방비하며
yet you dream of controlling heavenly law.
천도를 손에 쥐려고만 한다니
Ridiculous.
웃기는군
So what?
그럼 어떤데?
No matter how well Qingcheng hid you,
청성이 너를 아무리 잘 숨겼어도
you shall end up in my hands.
건목은 결국 본좌 손에 잡혔는데
I'll refine you into a vessel
본좌가 너를 노정으로 삼아
and absorb all your spirit energy
네 영기를 전부 흡수하면
to become the supreme cultivator.
천하제일이 될 것이다
Then I will unify all immortal sects,
그때 가서 선문을 통일하고
wipe out the demon clan,
마족을 멸하고
and rewrite the world's rules.
이 세상의 규칙을 새로 세울 것이다
As the saying goes,
이것이 바로
those who obey me shall thrive;
나를 따르는 자는 흥하고
those who oppose me shall perish.
거스르는 자는 망하는 것이다
Cuixuan,
사형
dozens of immortal sects are breaking the barrier,
수십 선문 문파가 산밖 결계를 뚫고 들어와
claiming they wish to see the Divine Tree.
건목을 보겠다고 합니다
How did they learn that?
그들은 어떻게 건목의 일을 안 것이냐?
What one does,
사람이 하는 일은
heaven witnesses.
하늘이 다 지켜보고 있는 법
Do you think you can hide everything
너는 네가 모두를 속이고
and control all under heaven?
하늘을 가릴 거라 생각했느냐?
Elder Cuixuan,
취현 장로
since the Divine Tree is in your possession,
건목이 당신들 손에 있다면
why keep it concealed?
왜 숨기고만 있습니까?
What do you plan to do with it next?
앞으로 어떻게 처리할 생각입니까?
Matters of the Wuyue Court
우리 무월정의 일은
hardly require any explanation to you.
여러분께 일일이 설명할 필요는 없습니다
That's not how it works.
그렇게 말씀하시면 안 되죠
The demon clan has run rampant lately.
근래 마족이 날뛰어
Many immortal cultivators have fallen victim.
우리 선문 동도가 큰 피해를 보았고
The Sea Calamity is also drawing near.
해운의 위기가 코앞으로 다가왔으니
The Divine Tree concerns the safety
건목은 모든 선문
of every sect
심지어 중토 전체의 안위와
and the Central Plains.
연관이 있는데
How can you claim
어찌
it's only Wuyue Court's business?
당신 문파만의 일이라 할 수 있습니까?
Am I right, everyone?
안 그렇습니까?
- Yes. - Exactly!
- 맞네 - 맞습니다
Yeah.
맞습니다
In the wars against demons years ago,
옛날 정마대전 때
Dizang Sect's ancestors were wounded by the Divine Tree.
우리 지장문 선배들은 건목 때문에 다치셨습니다
It owes our sect a blood debt
건목은 우리 지장문에 빚을 진 것인데
that cannot be ignored.
어찌 그냥 넘어갈 수 있습니까?
True!
맞습니다
The Divine Tree also harmed our ancestors.
건목은 우리 선조님들도 해쳤습니다
We must stand united
이런 해외 이물을 상대할 때는
against this outsider.
함께 원수를 갚아야 마땅하지요
Indeed.
옳습니다
We ought to deal with it together
함께 갚아야 합니다
and discuss a solution side by side.
방책을 함께 논해야 합니다
Everyone, listen!
여러분, 여러분
You've all traveled far today.
오늘 멀리서 와주셨으니
You may rest first.
일단 쉬시는 것이 어떻습니까?
Word spreads that the Divine Tree colludes with the demon clan.
건목은 이미 마족과 결탁했다고 들었는데
Every day we delay
하루라도 더 쉬면
brings greater peril.
위험이 그만큼 더 커질 것이니
We must resolve this without delay.
빨리 처리하는 것이 좋겠지요
I share
원군의 고려는
your worries.
본좌도 생각해 본 적이 있습니다
That is why I sealed all news
그래서 소식을 막고
and imprisoned the Divine Tree.
건목을 가둔 것이지요
Yet
하지만
since you have gathered here,
다들 이곳에 모였으니
tomorrow, I shall hold a public trial
내일 본좌는 여러분과 함께
of the Divine Tree with all of you.
건목을 심문할 것인데
What do you say?
다들 어떻게 생각하십니까?
Zhaomin.
소민 사저
Elder Cuixuan has laid secret restriction spells
취현 사백께서 무월사 안팎에
all around the Wuyue Shrine.
금제비경을 설치했으니
Do not force your way in.
무작정 뚫고 들어가면 안 됩니다
Later, Zhaomin and I
그때 제가 소민 사저와 함께
will draw off the guards outside.
밖의 수위병들을 유인할 테니
Use this to slice open
이것을 쓰면
the barrier temporarily.
결계를 가를 수 있습니다
But Elder Cuixuan will sense it for sure,
하지만 사백께서도 알아차리실 테니
so you must move fast.
빨리 움직여야 합니다
If you fail to rescue Lifei in time,
만약 려비를 제때 구하지 못했다면
retreat at once.
바로 철수하고
We'll rethink our plan.
다른 방책을 꾸며야 합니다
Deng and I cannot openly defy our sect.
저와 등 사제는 사문과 맞설 수 없으니
We appreciate you risking your lives.
두 분께서 수고하십시오
Thank you both on behalf of Lifei.
사매 대신 감사드립니다
No need for formalities.
사저, 너무 격식 차리지 마세요
Lifei is family to me.
려비도 제 가족이나 다름없으니
I'll save her no matter what.
당연히 구하러 가야죠
This is nothing like what happened in Duanming City.
하지만 이번은 단명성 때와 다릅니다
If Elder Cuixuan catches us,
만약 취현 사백께 들키면
we'll be branded traitors
선문에서
colluding with outsiders,
이물과 결탁한 반역자가 되고
and we might even lose our lives.
목숨도 위태로워질 수 있습니다
Last time in Duanming City,
지난번 려비가 단명성에서
Lifei risked her life for the Jiufeng Clan.
우리 구봉족을 위해 목숨 걸고 모험해 줬으니
My clan always repays kindness.
우리 구봉족은 은혜를 꼭 갚을 겁니다
What about the Wanxian Sect?
그럼 만선문은...
The Sea Sects have always been seen
저희 해파는 본래
as outsiders by the Mountain Sects.
산파 눈에 이물 같은 존재입니다
My master approved our trip here.
이번에 온 것도 사부님께서 허락하셨으니
I don't mind getting dragged
연루된다 해도
into trouble.
두렵지 않습니다
Cuixuan must be troubled by those immortal sects.
사형 사부는 이 선문들 때문에 근심이 가득할 것이겠네요
So,
어때요?
have you agreed on how to split my power?
저를 나눌 방도를 의논했나요?
We'll decide what to do with you
내일 진시에
after the public trial tomorrow
심판이 끝나고 나면
at Chen hour.
처분할 방도가 있을 것이다
I once
소사매
asked you to be my cultivation partner
전에 너를 나의 도려로 삼아
and practice with me,
함께 쌍수 수련하자고 했을 때
yet you refused time and again.
온갖 핑계로 거절하더니
Never thought
오늘 이 지경이
you'd end up like this today.
될 줄은 몰랐네
I thought you still held old affection
저는 사형이 옛정을 잊지 않고
and came to see me.
저를 보러 온 줄 알았더니
Turns out you're just here to gloat.
비웃으러 온 거군요
I do have a lingering fondness for you.
당연히 옛정은 조금 남아 있지
If you change your mind,
만약 네가 마음을 돌리면
I might take you away.
사형은 너를 데리고 나갈 수도 있다
Can you undo
제 몸을 가둔 이 사슬을
these chains on me?
풀 수 있습니까?
Seems we were never fated to be together.
우린 인연이 아닌가 보다
Since things cannot go as we wish,
뜻대로 되지 않으니
why not
차라리
share some
네 영기를
of your spirit energy with me?
사형한테 나눠 주어라
You also want my spirit energy?
사형도 제 영기를 흡수하고 싶으신가요?
You're doomed anyway.
어차피 사매는 피할 수가 없을 테니
Leave a trace of your energy for me.
사형에게 추억이라도 남겨주어라
Very well.
하긴
Better to give it to you
취현 그 여우에게 이득을 주는 것보다는
than let that old villain Cuixuan seize it.
사형한테 주는 게 더 낫죠
You treated me kindly once, after all.
그래도 예전에 저를 잘 대해주셨으니까
Rest assured.
걱정 마라
I'll be gentle,
사형이 부드럽게 해주겠다
and you won't suffer any pain.
절대 아프지 않을 거다
You worry too much.
사형, 생각이 많으셨네요
I'm bound by spirit-sealing chains,
저는 지금 쇄령사슬에 묶여서
unable to move an inch.
움직이지 못하니
No need to be so cautious.
걱정할 것 없습니다
You planned to use spirit absorption against me.
영흡으로 날 상대하려는 거구나
Cunning as ever, Lifei.
사매 역시 교활하네
Death draws near,
죽게 됐는데도
yet you still scheme against me.
꾀를 써서 나를 속이려 하다니
Then do not blame me
그렇다면
for showing no mercy.
이 사형이 무정해도 탓하지 마라
What's this?
이건 무엇이냐?
You want the Divine Tree's power, right?
건목의 힘을 원한다면서요?
Take it.
줄게요
Lifei!
려비
What brings you here?
여긴 어떻게 왔어요?
It won't work.
소용없어요
Let me try again.
다시 시도해 보겠소
There has to be a way.
방도가 있을 거요
Even the Wuyue Court's treasures
무월정의 보물이라 해도
cannot break these chains.
이 사슬을 풀 수 없다
Better spare the effort.
괜히 힘 빼지 마라
Useless fools!
쓸모없는 것들
Out of respect for Mr. Shen,
심 선생님의 체면을 보아
I shall spare your lives for now.
당장 너희를 죽이지는 않겠다
You may stay and accompany her
너희는 남아서
through her final moments.
그녀와 함께 마지막 길을 가야지
I've dragged you into trouble.
제가 누를 끼쳤네요
Truth is, I'm...
사실 저는...
The Divine Tree.
건목이잖아요
We already know.
우리 다 알고 있어요
We suspected it back in Duantu.
단도에 있을 때 이미 짐작했거든요
Tongzhou and Xiuyuan must have known, too.
동주와 수원도 분명 알고 있을 겁니다
That's why they sent Miaoqing to stand in for you.
아니면 묘청으로 그대를 대신하지 않았겠죠
So many have suffered because of me.
제가 너무 많은 사람들한테 누를 끼친 것 같아요
Gelin,
가림
as you knew my identity all along,
제 신분을 진작 알았으면
you never should have come.
오지 말았어야죠
Don't talk nonsense.
무슨 소리예요?
We knew each other young
다들 어린 시절부터
and walked through things together.
함께 지내왔는데
Because you're the Divine Tree,
그대가 건목이라서
you cease to be one of us?
더 이상 우리의 벗이 아닌 거예요?
What?
왜요?
The Divine Tree looks down on us?
건목 선자가 우릴 무시합니까?
Think we're not worthy to be your friends?
우리가 벗으로서는 부족하다는 겁니까?
We'll always be friends.
우린 영원히 벗이지요
I just...
한데...
Don't worry.
걱정 말아요
Chongyi and Zhaomin are working on a plan.
그대 사부님과 사저께서도 방도를 생각하고 있습니다
We will get you out for sure.
꼭 여기서 구해낼 겁니다
Where's Xiuyuan?
수원은요?
I heard the demon clan took him hostage.
마족에게 납치됐다고 들었는데
Is his life in danger?
위험한 거 아닐까요?
He
그는
should be fine.
위험하지는 않을 겁니다
With his cultivation and wits,
뇌 사제의 수위와 심지로 볼 때
he'll turn misfortune into safety.
반드시 화를 면할 거요
But what about you?
하지만 그대는 어떡하오?
Tomorrow's public trial
내일 선문에서 심판하는데
will have every sect watching.
수많은 사람들이 보는 앞에서
No one knows
어떻게 그대를
what they'll do to you.
처분할지도 모르오
I've been waiting for this trial.
저는 심판을 기다리고 있을 뿐입니다
Disguising herself as the Chufeng Academy's disciple,
건목은 추봉서원 제자로 분장하고
the Divine Tree infiltrated the Wuyue Court
무월정으로 잠입해
with malicious schemes.
꾀를 꾸몄습니다
I've found and captured her alive
지금 본좌에게 간파되어 붙잡혔으니
for this public trial.
이곳에서 심판을 진행하겠습니다
Fellow cultivators,
여러 선문 동도들은
do you have any questions?
이 일에 대해 의문 있으십니까?
Immortal Cuixuan,
취현 진인
I believe none of us will raise objections.
다들 이의는 없을 거라 믿습니다
Everyone,
여러분
Lei Xiuyuan is a demon spy,
뇌수원은 마족의 세작입니다
and Jiang Lifei is equally guilty.
이 요녀도 연루된 죄를 피할 수 없습니다
In my opinion, no need for a trial.
제 생각에는 심판할 것 없이
The Divine Tree must not remain in the world.
건목은 세상에 남겨둘 수 없다고 봅니다
Mr. Luo speaks the truth.
나 선생 말이 옳습니다
The previous Divine Tree helped the Demon Lord Yecha
지난 세대 건목은 악당
slaughter countless cultivators.
마군 야차를 도와 선문을 도륙했으니
Today,
오늘
we shall make her pay back
그녀한테서 그 빚을
every last debt she owes us.
전부 돌려받아야 합니다
Exactly.
맞습니다
Blood for blood.
피에는 피로 갚아야지요
The Divine Tree draws boundless spirit energy
건목의 영기가 천지에서 비롯되어
from heaven and earth.
무궁무진하니
I say
제 생각에는
we all absorb her energy together
다 함께 그녀의 영기를 흡수하여
to boost our cultivation,
수위를 올리지요
fend off the Sea Calamity,
해운을 막고
and defeat the demon clan.
마족을 물리칩시다
Fend off the Sea Calamity! Defeat the demon clan!
해운을 막고 마족을 물리칩니다
Enough!
그만하십시오
All of you!
당신들...
Can you all not contain your greed?
너무 급한 거 아닙니까?
The crimes of the old Divine Tree are not hers to bear.
지난 세대 건목은 지난 세대의 일일 뿐
In White Cliff and Duanming City,
백애와 단명성에서
Lifei only saved lives.
려비는 오직 사람을 구했을 뿐
She has never harmed a single innocent soul,
무고한 자들을 해친 적은 없습니다
and every one of you
이 사실을
knows this full well.
누구보다 다 잘 알고 있잖습니까?
What is this?
왜요?
Just because she bears the Divine Tree's power,
그녀가 건목의 힘을 갖고 있어서
you seek to plunder her spiritual energy
시비도 가리지 않고
without distinguishing right from wrong?
그녀의 영기를 빼앗으려 하는 겁니까?
If that is your intent,
만약 그런 거라면
let me ask you all.
묻고 싶습니다
How are you any different
이런 짓을 하는 당신들은
from the demon clan?
마족과 뭐가 다릅니까?
You...
당신...
The Sea Calamity shall ruin the world,
해운이 세상을 멸망시킬 때
and the innocents will perish.
창생은 무슨 죄가 있었습니까?
Capturing the Divine Tree
이번에 건목을 얻게 된 것은
is heaven's blessing,
하늘이 우릴 감싸주신 증거입니다
a sign that this power is meant to serve us.
건목은 반드시 우리 선문이 차지해야 한다는 것이죠
We must not cling to misplaced mercy
우리는 연민의 감정에 억눌려
and waste the blessing.
하늘의 뜻을 저버려서는 안 됩니다
Immortal Cuixuan speaks the truth.
취현 진인의 말씀이 옳습니다
We must follow heaven's will,
우리는 하늘의 뜻에 따라
slay the Divine Tree,
건목을 죽이고
and absorb her spirit energy!
영기를 흡수해야 합니다
Slay the Divine Tree! Absorb her energy!
건목을 죽이고 영기를 흡수하자
Ridiculous.
웃기는군
Absorb my energy?
영기를 흡수하자
You're all absurd.
정말 웃기는군
Insolent witch!
이런 요녀가 감히
Your end draws near. What's so funny?
죽기 직전인데 웃고 있느냐?
I laugh at your naivety.
당신들이 너무 순진한 게 웃길 뿐이다
Do you believe Cuixuan will share
정말 취현이 너희와 함께
my energy with all of you?
건목을 나눌 거라 생각하느냐?
How blind can you be?
참으로 멍청하구나!
Witch,
요녀야
cease your deceitful words to sow discord!
그런 말로 사람들을 현혹하지 마라
Immortal Cuixuan is noble and selfless,
취현 진인은 품격이 높고
devoted to the greater good.
대의를 품고 계신다
Never try to sow discord.
이간질하려 들지 마라
The greater good?
대의라니
Do you see these chains binding me?
내 몸에 채워진 사슬을 보아라
Jiang Lifei,
강려비
these chains look extraordinary.
그 사슬은 기이하긴 한데
What is the story behind them?
무슨 말을 하고 싶은 거야?
Lady Longjing,
용정 원군
you once aided me
나를 도운 적이 있으니
and have seen through many things.
아무것도 모르는 사람이 아닌가 보다
I'll tell you the truth out of goodwill.
그러니 너에게 사실을 알려주겠다
Cuixuan designed
이 수룡쇄령사슬은
these dragon-binding spirit-sealing chains solely to subdue
취현이 우리 사부님 청성을 상대하기 위해
my master Qingcheng.
특별히 만들어낸 것이다
They have fused deep into my bones and blood.
이 사슬은 이미 내 뼈와 피에 스며들었으니
If you absorb my spirit energy,
당신들이 만약 내 영기를 흡수한다면
the sealing spell will transfer into your bodies.
이 쇄령술법은 당신들 체내로 옮겨갈 것이다
Then each of you
그때 가서
will become Cuixuan's puppets.
당신들은 모두 취현의 괴뢰가 될 것이다
Devious witch!
이 요녀가 참 교활하군
You're misleading everyone.
감히 사람들을 현혹하려 하다니
Don't trust
요녀의 말을
a monster's lies.
어찌 믿습니까?
We are fellow immortal cultivators.
다들 같은 선문들인데
Why would I harm any of you?
본좌가 어째서 당신들에게 해를 끼치겠습니까?
Because you want to stand supreme under heaven.
당연히 네가 천하제일이 되기 위한
Driven by this ambition,
야심 때문이지
you murdered your senior brother Qingcheng,
너는 동문 사형인 청성을 죽이고
consorted with demons,
마물과 같은 편이 되면서
and drained stray spirits from foreign lands.
해외 잔령들을 흡수하였는데
There is no evil you would not commit.
무슨 짓을 못 하겠느냐?
Now that you possess me,
이제 건목을 손에 넣었으니
you'd never share my energy with others.
남에게 나눠줄 리가 없지
Qingcheng is dead?
청성 사형이 죽었다고?
He perished
사부님은
in Cuixuan's miniature realm.
취현의 소천세계에서 죽었다
You may verify this
당신들, 호사봉
at his former residence on Hushe Peak.
청성 사부님의 거처를 조사해 봐도 된다
Cuixuan,
취현
was what she said the truth?
강려비 말이 사실입니까?
Guangwei,
광미
do not believe her slander.
요녀의 말을 믿으면 안 된다
Witch,
요녀야
stop clouding our judgment.
헛소리하지 마라
Do you think sowing discord among us
이간질을 하면
will spare your life?
살아남을 거라 생각하느냐?
Zhaomin,
사저
I'm thirsty.
목이 말라요
Watch out, it's a trap!
조심하라
Qingcheng.
사형
Qingcheng!
사형!
If they saw you kill my master
그들이 네가 내 사부님을 죽이고
and piles of bones in the miniature realm,
소천세계에 쌓여진 백골들을 보게 된다면
would they still buy your lies?
네 말을 계속 믿을 것 같으냐?
The miniature realm has been destroyed.
소천세계는 이미 파괴되었다
No one will believe a word
네가 하는 말들은
of what you say.
아무도 믿지 않을 것이다
I've long heard that Qingcheng's Senluo Grand Art
청성 사형의 삼라대법에
can trace back to past events.
회소의 힘이 있다는 걸 듣긴 했었는데
So she is really his disciple.
그녀는 역시 사형의 제자였군
I'll refine you into a vessel
본좌가 너를 노정으로 삼아
and absorb all your spirit energy
네 영기를 전부 흡수하면
to become the supreme cultivator.
천하제일이 될 것이다
Then I will unify all immortal sects,
그때 가서 선문을 통일하고
wipe out the demon clan,
마족을 멸하고
and rewrite the world's rules.
이 세상의 규칙을 새로 세울 것이다
As the saying goes,
이것이 바로
those who obey me shall thrive;
나를 따르는 자는 흥하고
those who oppose me shall perish.
거스르는 자는 망하는 것이다
Why?
어째서...
Why did you kill Qingcheng?
어째서 청성 사형을 죽였습니까?
You two used to be the closest friends.
옛날에는 사이가 가장 좋았잖습니까?
He colluded with monsters
청성은 요괴와 결탁해
and sheltered demons,
마족을 감싸주었으니
making him a traitor to all immortal sects.
선문의 반역자다
I had every right
본좌가 죽였다 한들
to slay him.
무슨 잘못이 있단 말이냐?
You killed him,
그를 죽였으면
so I will avenge him!
제가 반드시 그 원수를 갚아야지요
Chongyi.
충이 사형
- Let me go! - Cuixuan.
- 막지 마라 - 사형
- Calm your rage. - Release me!
- 노여움을 푸십시오 - 이거 놔라
Let go of me!
놓으라고
Facing the Sea Calamity,
해운이 곧 닥치는데
don't turn on one another.
내전을 일으켜선 안 됩니다
We care nothing
청성이든 뭐든
for your sect's feuds
그건 당신들 무월정의 일이고
over Qingcheng.
우리는 전혀 관심이 없습니다
Today, we must absorb the Divine Tree's power.
오늘에는 반드시 건목을 흡수할 겁니다
Exactly.
맞습니다
The Divine Tree will only bring disasters.
여러분, 건목을 남기면 큰 화근이 될 겁니다
I say
제 생각에는
we consume her power together.
다들 함께 나누어 흡수하지요
You think you can absorb the power?
네놈들 따위가 감히 건목을 흡수하려고?
All those peerless, extraordinary talents
세상을 놀라게 한 인재들은
perished centuries ago.
수백 년 전 모두 세상을 떠났고
Only mediocre folk like you remain,
남은 건 모두 네놈들처럼 평범한 놈들일 뿐
occupying positions yet accomplishing nothing.
자리만 차지할 뿐, 아무런 공적도 세우지 못한 것들
For you to absorb the power
건목이 네놈들에게 흡수당하면
is akin to burning lutes to cook cranes,
불에 태워 없어지는 것이고
a waste of divine treasure.
천물을 낭비하는 것이다
Far better to channel all its power into me alone.
차라리 본좌의 능력을 높이는 게 낫다
With my strength,
본좌의 실력으로는
I can withstand the Sea Calamity
충분히 해운을 막고
and wipe out the demon clan.
마족을 멸할 수 있다
Have you lost your mind?
정신이 나갔습니까?
Cuixuan,
취현
you're talking nonsense.
대체 무슨 소리를 하는 것입니까?
Guangwei,
광미
you were gravely wounded by Yecha,
너도 예전에 야차에게 중상을 입어
stunting your cultivation forever.
수위가 더 이상 진보하지 못하게 되었잖느냐
Don't you wish to wipe away this humiliation?
원한을 갚고 싶지 않으냐?
I stand irreconcilably against the demon clan.
나는 마족을 절대 용납할 수 없습니다
Yet all you've done
하지만 사형이 하는 짓은
is no different from them.
마족과 다를 바 없지 않습니까?
You are stubborn beyond reasoning.
너도 고집만 세고 깨닫지 못하는 놈이군
You...
이런...
Cuixuan,
사형
turn back
이젠 그만하십시오
while there is still time.
더 이상 잘못된 길로 가지 마십시오
What are you trying to do?
뭘 하고 싶은 것이냐?
Move aside.
다들 비켜라
Move aside!
비켜라!
The Divine Tree belongs to the Lantian Sect!
건목은 우리 남천파의 것입니다
No, it belongs to the Dizang Sect!
건목은 지장파의 것입니다
- Seize it! - Hurry, move!
- 뺏어라 - 얼른 뺏어
- Hurry. - Go after her!
- 가자, 어서 - 따라와
Protect Lifei!
려비를 지켜라
The Divine Tree is ours!
건목은 우리의 것이다
Stay back!
오지 마라
Guard Lifei at all costs!
려비를 지켜라
The Divine Tree is ours.
건목은 우리의 것이다
She is ours!
우리의 것이다
Don't fight us for her.
빼앗지 마라
No one can take her from us!
아무도 건목을 빼앗지 못한다
Move aside!
비켜
Step away!
물러나라
Hand her over to us.
건목을 우리에게 넘겨라
She's ours!
우리의 것이다
She is ours.
건목은 우리의 것이다
She belongs to our sect!
우리 문파의 것이다
Step aside!
비켜라
Ours.
우리의 것이다
Master,
사부님
are they the ones you swore to protect?
이게 사부님께서 지키고 싶은 사람들입니까?
- Move aside! - This treasure is ours!
비켜라, 우리의 것이다
She's ours.
우리의 것이라고
Lifei!
소사매
The Divine Tree is ours.
건목은 우리의 것이다
She is ours.
우리 문파의 것이라고
- Give her to me! - Move aside!
당장 비켜라
The Divine Tree belongs to our sect!
건목은 우리 문파의 것이다
Master,
사부님
I've done all I could.
소봉추는 최선을 다했습니다
- Give her to me! - Now!
이리 내놔, 빨리 내놔
Demonic energy!
마기다
Channel your cultivation to resist it!
다들 공을 펼쳐 막아내라
♪If the seal can't be broken, then let it go♪
♪얽매인 봉인을 풀 수 없다면 차라리 내려놓으리♪
♪Where the heart finds peace, there is home♪
♪내 마음 편히 쉴 곳이 곧 나의 집이어라♪
♪Side by side, we fly through seas of clouds, break through the waves♪
♪비익조가 되어 구름바다를 가로지르고♪
♪The heart's ocean knows no shore♪
♪거친 파도를 깨부수니 마음의 바다는 끝이 없어라♪
♪Always, at the very end of fate♪
♪언제나 가혹한 숙명의 그 끝자락에서♪
♪Comes that one moment of defiance♪
♪끝까지 모질게 버텨내던 그 순간♪
♪In the human world or above, like flowing water♪
♪천상과 인간 세상사 모두 흐르는 물과♪
♪And falling petals♪
♪지는 꽃 같으니♪
♪Let this fleeting life be whatever it may♪
♪덧없는 이 허무한 삶을 그저 순리에 맡기리라♪
Xiuyuan?
수원
So he is the one
금색 눈동자를 가진 자가
with golden eyes.
그였군
Xiuyuan is Yecha?
수원이 야차였다고?
Divine Lord?
그가 신군이란 말인가?
What scent is this?
이 향기는 무엇인가?
Qingcheng sealed her origin
청성 사형이 그녀의 영식을 숨기기 위해
to hide her spirit aura.
그녀의 본원을 봉인했습니다
Now she is regaining her Divine Tree physique.
이제 그녀는 건목의 몸을 회복할 겁니다
I'll take you away.
내가 너를 데리고 가겠다
Yecha,
야차
meet your end!
죽어라
Cuixuan,
취현
the five-century feud between you
너와 우리 마족 사이 오백 년의 원한을
and my clan ends today.
이제 청산할 때가 됐다
Who dares seize my Divine Tree?
누가 감히 내 건목을 빼앗으려 하느냐?
Xiuyuan!
수원
Are you alright?
괜찮아요?
You said
너는 영원히
you'd always be Lei Xiuyuan.
뇌수원일 거라 말했었잖아
Have you forgotten it?
다 잊었어?
Five centuries have passed.
오백 년이 지났군
My clan shall finally wipe out all immortal sects.
우리 일족은 드디어 선문을 멸할 수 있게 되었네
The Fruit of the Divine Tree is within your grasp.
건목의 실이 눈앞에 있으니
My Lord, please enjoy it.
존상님께서 드십시오
Xiuyuan.
수원
Lei Xiuyuan!
뇌수원
Don't forget the original intent of your practice.
네 수련의 마음을 꼭 기억하거라
It ends like this again.
또 이런 결말이네
Is this
이대로
truly the end?
끝인 건가?
[The Eternal Fragrance]
[천향] [십사랑 소설  각색 작품]
♪The warmth within my arms♪
♪품 안에 가득했던 그대의 온기♪
♪I can no longer hold on to♪
♪내 이제는 끝내 붙잡지 못하네♪
♪In the cold night, how can I♪
♪시린 이 겨울밤, 그대를 어떻게 다시♪
♪Keep you warm until sunrise?♪
♪동이 틀 때까지 따스하게 품어줄까♪
♪My heartbeat freezes♪
♪가슴은 차갑게 얼어붙고♪
♪I can no longer tell you♪
♪마음을 전할 길조차 없는데♪
♪Looking you in the eyes, I cannot♪
♪그대 눈을 보며 하려던 그 한마디♪
♪Utter that line♪
♪끝내 입 밖으로 내지 못하네♪
♪Knowing love and hate♪
♪애증과 아픔, 깊어진 상처가 밀려와♪
♪Pain and wounds cannot be stopped♪
♪차마 막을 수 없음을 알면서도♪
♪I still linger on♪
♪난 여전히 그대를 그리워하며♪
♪Unwilling to let go of every inch of our past♪
♪겹겹이 쌓인 지난날을 놓지 못하네♪
♪Last night's stars cast faint glimmers♪
♪어젯밤 하늘을 수놓던 아스라한 별빛♪
♪But we thought nothing of it♪
♪그때는 어찌 당연하게 여겼을까♪
♪With a heartbroken cry♪
♪가슴이 찢어지는 듯한 애달픈 외침으로♪
♪I wish you well♪
♪오직 그대의 안녕만을 바라네♪
♪Knowing right and wrong♪
♪옳고 그름도, 흑백의 경계도♪
♪Black and gray are all illusions♪
♪검고 흐린 세상사 모두 부질없거늘♪
♪You're still screaming♪
♪그대는 여전히 목 놓아 울부짖으며♪
♪Running relentlessly without regret♪
♪미련 없이 거칠게 발버둥 치는구나♪
♪The storm looms, yet the wind stands in its way♪
♪몰아치는 비바람 온몸으로 막아서며♪
♪A final farewell left on the cliff♪
♪절벽 끝자락에 눈물로 새긴 서약♪
♪Leaping straight into♪
♪내 기꺼이 이 몸을 던지리라♪
♪That heartbreaking past♪
♪살을 도려내는 듯한 아픈 기억 속으로♪
♪Just to keep you safe♪
♪그대만 무사할 수 있다면♪
♪My breath is about to stop♪
♪내 숨결이 점차 희미해지고♪
♪Those hands can no longer hold yours♪
♪맞잡은 그 손을 더는 쥘 수 없으니♪
♪Through the future snow, wind, and fog♪
♪앞으로 다가올 시린 바람과 안개를♪
♪Who will be there by your side?♪
♪이제 누구와 함께 견뎌내야 할까♪
♪I smile as it ends♪
♪미소를 지으며 눈을 감는 것은♪
♪Afraid that you might cry for me♪
♪나로 인해 그대 슬피 울까 염려되어♪
♪Quietly, I turn into a sky lantern♪
♪말없이 공명등 한 줄기 빛이 되어♪
♪To light your way through the night♪
♪그대가 걷는 어두운 밤길을 비추어 주리♪
♪Knowing love and hate♪
♪애증과 아픔, 깊어진 상처가 밀려와♪
♪Pain and wounds cannot be stopped♪
♪차마 막을 수 없음을 알면서도♪
♪I still linger on♪
♪난 여전히 그대를 그리워하며♪
♪Unwilling to let go of every inch of our past♪
♪겹겹이 쌓인 지난날을 놓지 못하네♪
♪The storm looms, yet I stand in its way♪
♪닥쳐오는 비바람을 내 기어이 가로막으리♪
♪Torn inside, still I burn bright♪
♪가슴이 무너져 내릴지라도 참으로 감미롭구나♪
♪With the light from my fingertips♪
♪내 손끝에 맺힌 마지막 빛으로♪
♪I build a paradise♪
♪그대와 함께할 낙원을 세워♪
♪To wander with you♪
♪영원히 그대 곁을 거닐고 싶어라♪